# Gabriel Ballon Fox

Peru



gabriel.ballon.fox@gmail.com



+51959713815



linkedin.com/in/chinicooper

# Summary

I'm an industrial designer passionate about food design and software development. I've worked on a variety of projects, from product development (physical and digital) to brand creation. Also experienced in 3D manufacturing and fast prototyping.

## **Experience**



### **Product Designer**

Shio en Caja

Feb 2020 - Present (2 years 10 months +)

A personal project that explores the relationship between food - mental health and how we could use it to help people during the quarantine in Lima.

### **Frontend Developer**

**Angus Studio** 

Mar 2022 - Nov 2022 (9 months)

Web developer (Front-End & Back-End Developer) and UX/UI consultant.

## 😰 Seminario de Food Design

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú

Aug 2022 - Aug 2022 (1 month)

Dictar el primer taller/seminario de Food Design para la especialidad de Diseño Industrial en la PUCP.

### Web Developer

megawecare

Mar 2022 - Apr 2022 (2 months)

Upload a clone from the Thailand website, translate and create new pages for the Peruvian and Colombian subdomains.

### On Site Supervisor

Regina Maruyama - CASACOR 2019

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019 (3 months)

Supervised material usage and contractor hours to keep projects in line with budgets.

## Food Design Intern

Foodlosofia

Feb 2019 - Aug 2019 (7 months)

Create content for the brand and assist in the ideation process for food-related spaces, products and marketing strategies.

# Industrial Designer

Empanacombi

Aug 2016 - Aug 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Redesign the kitchen space to be more user-friendly toward handicap employees.

# **Food Event Designer**

Marca Perú

Mar 2018 - Apr 2018 (2 months)

Create a catering proposal based on the Casa Peru SXSW experience

# Research Intern

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú

Jan 2016 - Jan 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Develop projects about Food Design

### **Education**

### Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú

Bachelor's degree, Industrial and Product Design

Mar 2010 - Dec 2017

# Fundación Universitaria Internacional de La Rioja - UNIR

Master's degree, Diseño y Desarrollo de Interfaz de Usuario Web

Aug 2022 - Present

# **⊗**<sup>™</sup> Zero To Mastery Academy

Front End Developer

Mar 2020 - Present

### 🕨 Instituto Alta Cocina D'Gallia

Baking and Pastry Arts/Baker/Pastry Chef

Jan 2017 - Nov 2018

### Skills

Interaction Design • Product Development • Front-end Coding • Food & Beverage • User Interface Design • Front-End Development • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Teaching • Industrial Design • **Product Design**